#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

# Giuseppe Ronca

- Zijhuizen 5, 2011 Haarlem (The Netherlands)
- (+39) 3478147424

companies in 2007.

- x roncalabs@gmail.com
- https://roncaspot.github.io https://github.com/yehonal in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/giuseppe-ronca-b5216438/ @ https://www.facebook.com/giusepperonca/

Google Hangouts roncalabs@gmail.com

Sex Male | Date of birth 17 Apr 1990 | Nationality Italian

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a Computer Science addicted with a Bachelor's Degree.

I've 12 years of experience in software development and I usually spend my time making research and working in the field of IT

I started to work before my university career. I used to study IT since I was 13 years old. I've started with Pascal, TCL, C++, MySQL with which I've learnt the basics of programming languages, database administration and software architecture.

I wrote my first desktop and server applications for enterprises and big open source

Later on, I enrolled at the **University of Computer Science** in order to improve my software engineering skills, learn the AGILE framework as well as improving my skills in UX, Java, and design patterns.

I'm involved as the founder, lead developer and administrator of various **open-source** and non-profit communities with

thousands of active users such as AzerothCore

I had an experience as the **Manager** of my personal organizations (<u>Hyperweb2</u>, <u>Drassil</u>). I've recently organized <u>15 days of seminars</u> about **ReactJS and NodeJS**, with which I've created a team of 6 freelancers, the <u>Red Square team</u>. We've worked on various enterprise projects for which I played the role of both PM and Lead Developer.

I always look for perfect, effective and practical solutions to any potential problem.

Note: This template has been built using following tools:

1nd party: Universal-PWA Framework (based on ReactJS);

3rd party: jsPDF, Europass REST Api, wow.js, fontawesome.js, bootstrap.js, jquery

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 2007-Present

### Founder & Lead Developer

HyperWeb2, Cava De' Tirreni (Italia)

HyperWeb2 is a brand that since 2007 has been dealing with software development, consulting and technical assistance.

Aiming for quality and the continuous search for perfection.

I've developed dozens of Web sites and Mobile Applications with PHP or Nodejs/ReactJS Server for national and international customers.

Website: http://www.hyperweb2.com

### 01/09/2015-01/09/2016

### Lead Developer

Lenus Media, cava de' tirreni (Italy)

- Web Developing: Wordpress theme and plugin development. Proprietary PHP software (LenusLab suite)
- Crossplatform Mobile Applications with Apache Cordova and RESTful Architecture



Website: https://www.lenus.it/

#### 2006-Present

# Software developer

Mangos, TrinityCore & AzerothCore

Working as open source developer for MMO Server projects built with C++ & MySQL/PostgreSQL & founder of AzerothCore project.

<u>https://www.getmangos.eu/</u> (developer, nick: Yehonal)
<u>https://www.trinitycore.org/</u> (developer, nick: Yehonal)

http://www.azerothcore.org/ (founder)

#### 01/09/2010-01/01/2011

### Designer & Web Developer

Graffelab, cava de' tirreni (Italy)

Website developing

Reconstruction of logos, depliant and posters in vector graphics for screen printing

#### 01/05/2010-01/07/2010

# Developer

Intertexta Solutions, cava de' tirreni (Italy)

- Developer and Theme Designer for Joomla CMS

Website: http://intertexta.it

### 01/09/2009-01/01/2010

## Developer

7Web, cava de' tirreni (Italy)

- Developing proprietary CRM/CSM/ECommerce
- Main languages: Java & PHP

#### 01/06/2006-01/08/2007

#### **Technical Assistant**

Oasis Informatica, cava de' tirreni (Italy)

- Maintenance and Reparation of Computers
- Selling technology items

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### 2012-2019

# Information Technology

EQF level 6

University of Salerno, Department of Information Technology, Fisciano (Italy)

### Subjects:

- COMPUTER ARCHITECTURE
- MATHEMATICAL ANALYSIS
- OPERATIONAL RESEARCH
- DISCRETE MATHEMATICS
- PROGRAMMING
- PROGRAMMING 2 ^
- ALGORITHMS
- DATABASES
- PHYSICS
- SOFTWARE ENGINEERING
- ENGLISH
- HUMAN COMPUTER INTERACTION

- OPERATING SYSTEMS
- ADVANCED PROGRAMMING TECHNIQUES
- MATHEMATICAL AND STATISTICAL METHODS
- COMPUTER NETWORKS
- THEORY OF COMPUTATION
- DISTRIBUTED PROGRAMMING
- NUMERICAL ANALYSIS
- MOBILE PROGRAMMING
- WEB DEVELOPING
- DATA STRUCTURES

#### Thesis:

Unilance: the future of job

Marketplace for freelancers based on cryptocurrencies

#### 2007-2009

# I.T. High School

EQF level 5

I.T.I.S Focaccia, Salerno (Italy)

Computer science.

Programming languages: Java, delphi, c, c ++, php, asp.

Databases: MySQL, Access. Network management.

Electronics: circuits, telecommunications and modulation. Statistics, Algebra

### 2004-2006

### Scientific high school

A. Genoino, cava de' tirreni (Italy)

Subjects:

Science, Physics, Maths, Italian, English, French, Latin, Geography, History

### PERSONAL SKILLS

#### Mother tongue(s)

#### Italian

### Foreign language(s)

English Spanish French

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	C1	B1	B1	B2
A2	A2	A2	A2	A2
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

#### Communication skills

- Good communication skills acquired during salesperson job with an insurance company after a series of meetings.
- 05/03/2015 Seminar speaker on modular & distributed systems and virtual reality
- 09/2018 01/2019 Manager & Main Speaker on Enterprise Programming Seminar

## Organisational / managerial skills

Experience as administrator of teams related to MMORPG community Manager and Lead Programmer of MMO Server Development Team. I have an efficient research method for information on the Internet.



I really believe in the importance of intercommunication and project documentation. I am a big fan of version control systems for team and personal development. I love to find solutions to any kind of problem.

#### Job-related skills

Excellent skills to work in teams, organizing of working groups.

Expertise in using code versioning tools (git, svn, CSV, Mercurial HG).

Great ability in using debugging tools, testing, and documentation tools.

Advanced Experience with GNU/Linux

### Digital skills

	SELF-ASSESSMENT					
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem- solving		
Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user		

### Digital skills - Self-assessment grid

### Main Development Skills:

- JavaScript / NodeJS
- ReactJS
- GraphQL / Apollo Framework
- SQL Databases
- TypeScript / Angular
- jQuery
- HTML & CSS
- Bootstrap framework
- PHP
- Symfony framework
- Testing / Debugging
- C/C++
- Docker
- Apache Cordova/Phonegap
- Electron
- Bash Language
- VS / VS Code
- Java

### Secondary Skills:

- Webmin
- Proxmox
- Python
- Firebase
- Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Netbeans
- Eclipse
- L/W/X AMP
- Microsoft Office / Libre Office
- Unix-like & Windows OS
- ASP
- Pascal



#### Curriculum vitae

- TCL
- Matlab / Octave
- Android Studio
- Delphi

#### Services:

- Universal Applications: I can create applications that run of Browser, Mobile, and Desktop using technologies such as ReactJS, Electron, Phonegap, GraphQL and microservices.
- DevOps & System Admin: I can setup complex local and virtual networks on Linux OS. I love to dockerize applications and use container to create high-performance inftrastructures.
- Server Developer: I've developed various server applications using C++, NodeJS, Java, and PHP with API protocolos such as SOAP, REST, GraphQL and TCP Sockets
- Technical Assistance: I'm able to operate in any kind of fields when talking about Hardware and Software assistance. Working on computer repair since i was 13 years old

#### Other skills

#### Hobbies:

- Travel: Exploration is in my blood
- Photography: I love to take foto at world's beatiful things and places with my Lumix DSLR. I Love movies and any kind of visual art
- Music & Instruments: I'm tone-deaf. I love to play guitar and listen to music
- Videogames: Single player game lover and MMO developer
- Technology and hardware mods: I love technology stuff! I often repair hardware and software of any kind of device
- Science: I'm a sience enthusiast! I love to pull information online about new scientific research

#### Driving licence

AM, A1, A2, A, B

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# Projects RoncaSpot:

2019 - Personal website and resume developed with ReactJS using my modular Universal-PWA boilerplate

https://roncaspot.github.io

#### Projects Ease Platform:

2019 - Marketplace for Freelancers -

Stack: React/Redux/Nodejs/MySQL

https://www.itsease.com/

### Projects PlaceMe:

2019 - AirBnB "Clone"

for Boston University Students -

Stack: React/Redux/NodeJS/MongoDB

https://placemeliving.com/

## Projects 2019 - Recipe hybrid app and web

dashboard -

Stack: React/GraphQL/Apollo/NodeJS

#### Projects Sequelize-graphql-schema:



2019 - javascript library to

autogenerate graphql api based on sequelize models;

https://github.com/almost-full-stack/sequelize-graphql-schema

Projects Universal Node:

2019 - boilerplate for

server applications (NodeJS, GraphQL, Sequelize, MySQL,

SQLite)

https://github.com/HW-Core/universal-node

Projects Universal PWA:

2019 - boilerplate for pwa

and hybrid applications (React, GraphQL/Apollo) https://github.com/HW-Core/universal-pwa

Projects AzerothCore:

2017 -

**AzerothCore** 

(MMO Server - C++,

MySQL, PHP & Symfony, Nodejs) https://github.com/azerothcore

Projects App Framework: 2017 - framework to build TWA apps

(AngularJS/Apache Cordova)

https://github.com/Drassil/app-framework

Seminars RST Lab: 2018 - Enterprise Programming by Red Square Lab (Role: Main Speaker & Organizer).

Fullstack JS, C++, PHP

https://www.redsquareteam.eu/iscrizione-eventi

Projects Drassil Launcher:

2017 - Desktop and Mobile "Steam-like" application. Built with

cordova and electron

.

https://app.drassil.net

Projects Git Wiki:

2017/2018 - Static Wiki build for github/gitlab and Jekyll

https://github.com/Drassil/git-wiki

Seminars 2017 - From Cryptocoin to Cryptocurrency (Role: Guest)

Competition 2016 - 2th position with SOuL Project. Phonegap & Javascript stack (Role: Backend Developer)

Projects Palmapp:

2016- Hybrid mobile app developed with jquery, cordova, php for Palma Campania Town



### http://www.palmapp.it

Projects WP Contract Form:

2016- Wordpress Plugin to Sign Contract Forms https://github.com/hyperweb2/contract-form

Projects SOuL App:

2015 - Life Emergency & Reports (RESTFul crossplatform app -

Hw-Core Java server and Hw-Core JS frontend) https://github.com/soul-source/soul-app-full

Projects Directory Structure:

2014 - A Directory Structure Standard for any kind of project

https://github.com/HW-Core/directory-structure

Projects Hw-Core framework: 2011 - multilanguage framework & set of libraries to build apps

https://github.com/hw-core

Projects CavaMultimediale: 2010 - Abandonware

web porting (SPA - JS, Hw-Core JS Framework) https://github.com/Yehonal/cavamultimediale

Other Experiences

■ 21/10/2019 - Xebia Typescript Meetup (Role: Guest)

■ 2016 - Funded Drassil Organization www.drassil.org

■ 2012 - Linux Day (Role: Guest)

■ 2009 - Insurance Aspecta (Role: Consultant)